Finding Aid for the United Office and Professional Workers of America Records LSC.0963
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Office Files
  - Newspapers and Periodicals
    - Daily Worker. January-December 1947., 72 items. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      April 1; May 5, 8, 26.
      June 2, 8-10, 14, 30.
      July 4, 7, 11, 12, 15, 17, 19-22, 25, 26, 28, 29, 31.
      August 1, 2, 4, 5, 7-9, 11-16, 18, 19, 24.
      September 6, 10, 13.
      October 6, 8, 24, 28.
      November 20, 23, 25.
      December 5, 11, 12, 17, 28.
    - Daily Worker. January 1948-January 1949., 54 items. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      1948: January 6, 11, 23; February 18, 25, 27; March 3-5, 10, 24; April 3, 9, 23; May 5, 11, 17, 18, 20, 25; June 2, 4, 14, 17, 29; July 13; August 12, 17, 26; September 27, 28; October 20, 22, 24, 29; November 4, 5, 25, 26, 30; December 1, 2, 13, 17, 20, 21, 24, 29, 30.
      1949: January 7, 10, 12, 13, 16.
    - Office and Professional News. December 1944-June 1945., 1944, 1945; 5 items. (Box 20, Folder 3)
      1944: December, v.d.
      1945: January, February and June, v.d.
    - C.I.O. News, National and Washington State Editions. September 1944-May 1950., 1944-1950; 32 items. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Issues from National Edition: September 1944; January 1945; February and November 1946; May, July-September, November and December 1947; January, March, August, October and November 1948; May, July, October-December 1949; February, March and May 1950.
      Issue from Washington State Edition: October 1948.
    - NM (magazine). March 1946-August 1947., 1946, 1947; 6 items. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      March 5 and 26, 1946; January 7, March 4, April 22 and August 26, 1947.
    - San Francisco Labor Clarion. October 1946-September 1957., 1946-1948 and 1957; 18 items. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      1946: October 18, November 29 and December 6.
      1947: January 31, February 7, April 4 and 25; May 23 and 30; June 6 and 13; September 19; December 12.
      1948: January 23; February 20; March 12 and 26.
      1957: September 5.
    - The Worker. August 1947-February 1949., 1947-1949; 10 items. (Box 20, Folder 7)
      1947: August 3 and 17. 1948: Febraury 29; March 7; June 6; November 7 and 28.
      1949: January 23; February 13.
    - The Dispatcher. August-October 1947 and September 1950., 1947, 1950; 5 items. (Box 20, Folder 8)
      1947: August 8 and 22; September 5; November 3.
      1950: September 1.
    - Career. January 1949-June 1950., 1949-1950; 17 items. (Box 20, Folder 9)
      1949: January 1 and 15; March 15; April 1 and 15; May 1 and 15; June 1 and 15; July 1 and 15; August 15; September 1.
      1950: February 1; May 1 and 31; June 15.
    - Champion., 1950; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 10)
      1950: August.
  - Labor Issues - Clippings
    - Miscellaneous clippings., 1938-1953; 7 items. (Box 20, Folder 11)
      Articles from 1938: Herald Tribune, People's World, S.S.W.B, Business Week.
      Articles from 1939: Labor Front, San Francisco.
      Articles from 1947: Union Power, M.C.S. Voice.
      Articles from 1953: Unity News.
  - Newspapers and Periodicals
    - Daily People's World. September-December 1946 and n.d., 17 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      September 13, 16, 21, 26, 27, 30; October 4, 17, 21, 24, 31; November 20, 26, 29; December 7, 28.
    - Daily People's World. January-December 1947., 58 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      January 3, 15, 23, 30, 31; February 12; March 3, 21, 27, 28; April 3; May 5, 22, 24, 31; June 3, 5-7, 10, 14, 16, 18, 20, 23, 25; July 5, 7, 15, 18, 22, 24, 30, 31; August 4, 7-9, 12-15, 19, 20, 30; September 12, 18; October 21; November 5, 6, 20, 26, 28; December 2-4, 11, 22.
    - Daily People's World. 1-48 to 12-48., 1948; 50 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      January 7, 13, 24; February 13; March 1, 3, 12, 19, 23, 30; April 2, 12, 13, 15, 19, 21; May 7, 29; June 4, 10, 14, 16, 21, 23, 24; July 19-21; August 13, 17, 19, 20, 24; September 2, 9, 17; October 13; November 5, 23, 24, 26, 27, 29, 30; December 3, 8, 10, 27, 30, 31.
    - Daily People's World. January-March 1949., 7 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      January 3, 12, 25; February 3, 17, 24; March 21.
    - New York Herald Tribune (July 18, 1947), Oakland Tribune (October 15, 1947)., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - C.T.A.L. News. 10-47 and 12-47., 1947; 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 6)
      October 20, 27; December 1.
    - San Francisco Examiner (May 26), and San Francisco News (May 28)., 1948; 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Duplicates
    - Bulletins, newspapers, and clippings: duplicates. February 1945-May 1950., 1945-1950; 15 items. (Box 21, Folder 8)
      UOPWA Bulletin: February-June and September 1945.
      Labor Herald: April 22 and August 5, 1947; February 3 and March 16, 1948; May 3, 1949.
      Daily Worker: March 1, 1948.
      Career: May 15, July 15 and September 1, 1949; May 31, 1950.
  - Newspapers and Periodicals
    - Scrapbook - UOPWA maintained. April 1937-September 1938., 1937-1938; 61 items. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      San Francisco Chronicle: May-October 1937; December 1939; January-May 1940.
      San Francisco Examiner: July-October 1937; December 1939.
      L.H.: October-November 1937; November 1939.
      San Francisco News: May-October 1937.
      San Francisco C. Bulletin: May-July 1937.
      San Francisco News: 1938 (n.d.); November-December 1939.
      P.W.: September 1938; December 1939.
  - Labor Issues
    - Clippings - maintained by UOPWA. December 1939-December 1947 & n.d., 1939-1947 & n.d.; 205 items. (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Includes: San Francisco Chronicle, San Francisco C. Bulletin, San Francisco News, Labor Clarion, New York Times, New York Herald Tribune, New York World Telegaph, Honolulu Star Bulletin, Honolulu Advertiser, Spokane Daily Chronicle, Spokesman Review, Oakland Post, Dispatcher, Los Angeles Daily News, Labor Herald, P.W., P.M., and P.E.
    - Clippings - maintained by UOPWA. January-March 1948., 28 items. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Includes: Los Angeles Daily News, San Francisco News, New York Herald Tribune, New York World Telegram, New York Times, New York Sun, Brooklyn Eagle, Daily Worker, and P.M.
  - Publications
    - Personnel Practices in Factory and Office., 1940; Ringbound manual. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Studies in Personnel Policy no.23. National Industrial Conference Board, Incorporated, New York.
  - Publications by and about UOPWA
    - Insurance Career. vol.2 no.5 (May 1946). (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Publications by or about UOPWA
    - Staff. vol.1 no.1-4 (January 1946-May 1947). (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Technical America vol.1 no.1-5 (February-July 1947). (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Office and Professional News. vol.15 no.4 (April 1948). (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Welfare in Action. vol.1 no.1-3,5,6-8, 12 (1944), vol.2 no.1-5 (1945), vol.3 no.1-2 (1946), n.d., 1944-1946 and n.d. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Guild News (May 1940). (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - UOPWA Bulletin. vol.1 no.1-5 (1945). With special supplement to no.3. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Bookkeepers, Stenographers and Accountants Union
    - BS & AU Souvenir Journal (March 1937). With another copy. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Publications by or about UOPWA
    - Stenographers Ball - programs., 1938, 1940-1942; 4 items. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Newspapers and Periodicals
    - Modern Office Procedures. vol.14 no.3 (March 1969). (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Prudential Insurance
    - Who Runs the Uopwa? (November 1948). (Box 23, Folder 11)
      Prudential Insurance publication alleging Communist control of UOPWA.
  - Publications by or about UOPWA
    - Facts of Life. An economic document. UOPWA no.16-1., 1948 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Newspapers and Periodicals
    - March of Labor. vol.3 no.3-4 (March-April 1951). (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - New Republic. October 11, 1948. (Box 23, Folder 14)
      Cannibalism in the CIO, p.10.
    - Science & Society. vol.14 no.3 (1950). (Box 23, Folder 15)
      White collar unions and professional organizations, by Vera Shlakman, p.214.
    - Labor Unity. vol.8 no.4 (May 1933). (Box 23, Folder 16)
      White collar, by C. Albert, p.23.
    - New Masses. vol.56 no.10 (September 4, 1945) vol.62 no.1 (December 31, 1946) vol.64 no.4 (July 22, 1947)., 1945, 1946, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 17)
      White collar blues, by Richard Lewis, p.4 (1945), Capitulation is not the answer, p.12 (1946), and Portrait of an artist: Morris Topchevsky, by Larry Forhman, p.9.
  - Newspaper and Periodicals
    - Industrial Bulletin. vol.28 no.7 (July 1949). (Box 23, Folder 18)
      The typist at home, pp.38-39.
  - Bureau of Labor Statistics
    - Office mechanization. n.p., [1938]., 66pp. Typescript. With photographs. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      According to Richard Lewis, this was prepared for the Bureau of Labor Statistics and describes the history of clerical functions and the early history of office machines.
  - CIO
    - Statement of the California CIO Council., 1946; 2 copies. (Box 24, Folder 2)
      re amendment of the wage order and sanitary regulations for women and minors in professional, technical, clerical and similar occupations.
  - United States Department of Labor
    - Informal hearing... for the finance, insurance, real estate, motion picture, and miscellaneous industries., 1943 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Wage and Hour and Public Contracts Division.
    - Memorandum... for the finance, insurance, real estate, motion picture, and miscellaneous industries., 1943 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      Wage and Hour and Public Contracts Division. Economics Branch.
  - Bureau of Labor Statistics
    - Conference with research directors of national and international unions. Washington, D.C., 27-28 June 1950., 1940 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Proceedings. Bureau of Labor Statistics... research directors of national & international unions. Washington, D.C., 19-20 June 1941. (Box 24, Folder 6)
      Full title Proceedings. Bureau of Labor Statistics second annual conference with research directors of national and international unions.
    - Proceedings. Bureau of Labor Statistics... research directors of national and international unions. Washington, D.C., 17-18 June 1942. (Box 24, Folder 7)
      Full title Proceedings. Bureau of Labor Statistics third annual conference with research directors of national and international unions.
    - Office workers salaries, hours of work, supplementary benefits., 1948 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      re San Francisco and Oakland.
    - Monthly Labor Review. vol.71 no.1 (July 1950). (Box 24, Folder 9)
      With note on cover, pp.113-120, office workers salaries.
  - National Business and Professional Council Project
    - How starched are white collars today?, 1939? (Box 24, Folder 10)
      Womans Press, New York. In connection with National Business and Professional Council Project, Economic Security.
  - New York State Department of Labor
    - Cost of living for women workers [cover title]., 1941 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      Title page Adequate maintenance and protection of health for women workers in New York State, September 1940.
  - John Randolph Haynes and Dora Haynes Foundation
    - Haynes foundation budget for moderate income families. Prices for Los Angeles, September 1949. By Gloria S. Goldberg., 1950 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - National Industrial Conference Board, Incorporated
    - Job evaluation. Formal plans for determining basic pay differentials., 1950 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      Studies in personnel policy no.25.
  - Personnel Research Federation
    - Personnel Journal. vol.20 no.2 (June 1941). (Box 24, Folder 14)
      With note on cover, see p.51, esp. p.56. Incomplete issue.
  - UOPWA
    - Insurance Career. vol.1 no.1-4 (1945) vol.2 no.1-11 (1946)., 1945-1946 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Bound in 1 volume.
  - UOPWA - Northern California
    - Report. vol.1 no.1-11 (1946-1947?) vol.2 no.1-2 (1947-1948?)., 1946-1948 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - UOPWA
    - Ledger, The. vol.2 no.12 (1936) vol.3 no.1-11 (1937) vol.4 no.1-12 (1938)., 1936-1938 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Bound in 1 volume. Publication of the Bookkeepers, Stenographers, and Accountants Union, local 12646, A.F.L., and the National Committee of Office and Professional Workers Unions.
  - UOPWA - Industrial Insurance Agents Union
    - Debit, The. vol.1 no.1-2 (1937) vol.2 no.1 (1938) vol.4 no.6-8, 9-12 (1938) vol.5 no.1 (1939)., 1937-1939 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Bound with Insurance Career (December 1943) in 1 volume.
  - UOPWA
    - Insurance Career (December 1943). (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Bound with issues of The Debit in 1 volume.
  - United Electrical and Machine Workers of America
    - [Union organization]., n.d. (1940's?) (Box 25, Folder 5)
      According to notes by Richard Lewis, this film deals with organizing and collective bargaining in the electrical industry. The film is in poor condition, brittle and already broken in some places.
  - UOPWA
    - UOPWA News. vol.5 no.1-12 (1939) vol.6 no.1, 3-6, 8 (1940)., 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - UOPWA News. vol.7 no.1-12 (1941) vol.8 no.1-21 (1942)., 1941-1942 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - UOPWA News. vol.9 no.1-12 (1943) vol.10 no.1-12 (1944)., 1943-1944 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Bound in 1 volume. For 1944, 2 issues, July & August, are numbered 7. In November 1944 no.11 was issued in 2 parts.
    - UOPWA News. vol.11 no.1-2 (1945) vol.12 no.3-12 (1945) vol.12 no.1-12 (1946). (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Bound in 1 volume. Includes special V-J issue for August 1945.
    - UOPWA News. vol.14 no.1-12 (1947) vol.15 no.1-8 (1948)., 1947-1948 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Publications
    - Publications (ca. 1943 to 1949)., n.d.; 5 items. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Taxes to Win (C.I.O.), Operation Eisenhower, It's Your Union They're After (UE- United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America), Stop the Frame-ups Against Our Union (UE), How Big Is Big Business? (C.I.O.).
    - Publications., 1947; 2 items. (Box 27, Folder 2)
      [California]...of the People (Independent Progressive Party of California), Forecasts of the Population of the United States, 1945-1975 (U.S. Department of Commerce).
    - Publications., 1948; 2 items. (Box 27, Folder 3)
      The Cold War On American Labor, (National Labor Committee for Wallace and Taylor), Neither to Right Nor Left (C.I.O.).
    - Publications. 1949., 1 item. (Box 27, Folder 4)
      New Republic Special Section: State of the Union, A Program for Liberal America.
    - Publications. 1950., 2 items. (Box 27, Folder 5)
      The C.I.O. Today, by George Morris, The Vatican Conspiracy in the Trade Union Movement, by George Morris.
  - Newspapers and Periodicals
    - Economic Outlook. April 1944-December 1947., 1944-1947; 27 items. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Economic Outlook. January-May 1950., 1948-1950.; 28 items. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - American Statistician. December 1949., 1 item. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - March of Labor. June 1949., 1 item. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - March of Labor. February-December 1951., 7 items. (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - March of Labor. January-July 1952., 6 items. (Box 27, Folder 11)